<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="77171" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Realistic Trips" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="This mod allows you to configure the travel behavior for the city's population." />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
This mod has several options to configure the travel behavior of the population. There is also a feature to change the simulation to follow a weekly schedule, with travel patterns changing based on each day of the week. And there is another option to slow down time and make the day longer - without changing the simulation speed.

## Settings

The main settings menu allows the user to select predefined settings - which will change all the options of this mod. They are:

* **Performance:** This is option is similar to the Vanilla behavior (but not equal), it will spread trips throughout the day and night and doesn't have a big impact on performance.
* **Balanced:** This is the default setting, it has several of the realistic options, but without the features that cause a big impact on performance.
* **Country Settings:** Using a country setting will make travel behavior more realistic. Data for the different countries available are based on data collected from different surveys from each country. Current countries that are available are: Brazil, Canada, France, Germany, Netherlands, Phillipines, Poland, UK and USA.

If more control over the simulation is desired, the user can adjust the settings in the other sections defined below.

## Work

This section has several options to configure work travel behavior.

* **Work Arrival / Departure:** The "Delay/Early factor" adds greater variation to cims work arrival and departure times. The arrival/departure times are implemented using a normal distribution and it works differently in the morning and evening commutes to reflect the real world. In real cities, the evening commute tends to be more spread out than the morning commute, this happens because although most workers have a set time to arrive at work, when it is time to leave work the departure time is not as strict, with a few workers working a few extra minutes or hours. This feature is also implemented differently for each shift. The Evening and Night shifts have even greater variation, spreading out the start and end work times for the cims that work during those shifts.
* **Peak Spreading:** If this option is enabled, cims that have a very long commute will go to work earlier to try to avoid traffic. This is calculated by getting the commute time distribution of the population and selecting the 10% that has the highest travel time. Those cims, will leave to work 20% earlier.
* **Work Shifts:** Cims go to work based on three shifts: Day, Evening and Night. This mod allows you to configure the percentage of each of those work shifts, the base game has around 20-25% of work trips being at either the Evening or at Night. The mod options menu will allow you to set the percentage for Evening and Night shifts. Day shift percentage will correspond to the remaining percentage points. The default values of the mod are set for 6% for Evening shifts and 4% for Night shifts. These values come from a US Survey which can be found in this link: https://redline.digital/shift-work-statistics/
* **Lunch Break:** The lunch break option will add the possibility of some cims to leave work around noon for either Leisure or Shopping. The break lasts around an hour, after that, they will return to work. The lunch break can be configured by setting the lunch break probability in the mod's menu. Also, cims that take a lunch break, might leave work a little later (to compensate for the time that they weren't working).
* **Work Start/End Time Settings:** This option allows the user to change work start and end times for the day shift.
* **Part Time Settings:** This setting only applies to the day shift. The workers that are part time will either work in the morning or afternoon. Since their shift is shorter, they will not take a lunch break.
* **Remote Work Settings:** The portion of citizens that work remotely will stay at home and not go to work. They might still go out for a lunch break and then come back to work at home. Only workers with at least level 3 of education will work remotely and this only applied to Offices and City Services. The default value for remote work was calculated based on data from this link: https://www.forbes.com/advisor/business/remote-work-statistics/

## Leisure and Shopping

This section has some options to configure shopping and leisure behavior.

* **Disable Early Shopping or Leisure:** This option will significantly reduce shopping and leisure trips happening between Midnight and 6 AM. With this option, those trips will mostly start between 8 to 10 AM.
* **Vacation and Holiday System:** The vanilla game simulation works as a combination of a Weekday and a Weekend, with work and schools trips having a certain probability of not happening assuming that that cim is taking a day off. The vanilla probability is around 60% of not going to work or school. With vacation and holidays default settings, that probability will be around 30% for work trips.
* **Average Shopping Time for each Resource:** This option allows the configure the average shopping time in minutes for each resource. In the vanilla game, cims take will shop in an instant, with this option they will take longer to shop.

## School

This section has some options to configure school trips behavior.

* **School Vacation System** This feature works similar to the vacation and holiday system for work, with the difference that on Weekends schools are assumed to be closed.
* **School Start/End Time Settings:** This option allows the user to change school start and end times. The arrival and departure times won't be exact, they will vary following a normal distribution based on the times selected. The greated the education level of the student, the greater the variation will be.
* **School Attendance by Day of the Week:** This section allows the user to configure the attendance level for elementary schools, high school, and Colleges and Universities by day of the week. Default values were calculated from this source: https://ffteducationdatalab.org.uk/2022/12/weekday-attendance-analysis-a-new-report-for-schools/

## Week

This section has some options to configure the Mod's day type and week settings.

* **Day Type Simulation** The options in this menu will allow you to change the simulation from an Average Day, a Weekday, Saturday, Sunday or simulate a 7 Day Week. With the 7 Day Week option, each day will be a different day of the week, Monday to Thursday will function as a Weekday and Friday as an Average Day.. The current day of the week will be shown in the UI in the bottom left corner.

An Average Day, is similar to the vanilla default setting. It consists of a combination of Weekday and Weekends behavior, with around 30% of cims behaving as on a weekend and the rest as on a weekday.

On a Weekday, most of the trips will be work or school related. On a Weekend, there will be more Leisure and Shopping trips. Schools are closed on Weekends. Also, workers that work on weekend will have shorter shifts. Weekend shift duration was calculated from this source: https://www.bls.gov/charts/american-time-use/emp-by-ftpt-job-edu-h.htm

* **Slow Time and Increase Day Length** If enabled, this option will make the day longer - while keeping the simulation speed the same. The day length of the vanilla game when compared to the cim's travel times is not reasonable. It is commom to find cims that take around 2 in game hours to get from home to work and this is not realistic. Most major cities in the world have an average commute of 25 to 30 minutes, in my test city the average commute was around 1 hour and 40 minutes. Based on this, if this option is enabled I recommend that the reduction factor be set to 3.5. It is not recommended to change this setting in an existing city, doing so will affect citizens ages and can cause some problems. That will eventually be resolved over time as citizens age.
* **Days per Month** Default value is 1, if increased the number of days per month and year will change. This does affect the simulation, if with the default values it took 1 year (12 days) for a cim do age 1 year, with 2 days per month it will still take 1 year (24 days) for a cim to age 1 year.

In this section it is also possible to configure the percentage of workers that will go to work in each day of the week. This can be configured by work type, which include: Office, Commercial, Industry and City Services. The default values for these parameters were calculated from this source: https://www.bls.gov/news.release/flex2.t09.htm

## External Trips

This section has some options to configure external trips for tourists and commuters.

* **Tourism variation by day of the week** If enabled, there will be more tourists on the weekend and less tourists on weekdays. On Fridays (an Average Day) the number of tourists won't change.
* **Commuter variation by day of the week** If enabled, there will be more commuters on the weekend and less tourists weekdays. On Fridays (an Average Day) the number of commuters won't change. Commuters are workers that spawn from outside connections, in the vanilla game they can come into your city by car or train. This option also addes the possibility of them arriving by plane - which you can interpret as business travelers from other cities going into your city for business meetings.

## Traffic Reduction

In the Other tab, it is possible to configure the game's traffic reduction factor. The game default's value is 5. This factor is used to reduce traffic in the city by not simulation all citizens trips. A value of zero will have all citizens doing their trips. Note that this can affect performance.

## Special Events

Special events will happen at park facilities on specific times every day. The number of events per day will vary based on the day of the week. While a park facility is hosting an event, that facility will attract more visitors than normal. It is possible on check the events of the day by clicking on the mod's icon on the top left (see image). The settings below can be changed in the mods menu:

* **Min Attraction** Each park facility has a different attraction level. For example, a small playground has much lower attraction than a soccer field. Changing the value of this option will increase or descrease the park facilities that can host events.
* **Min and Max events by day of the week** Each day of the week can have a different number of events. The number of events is selected randomly based on the minimum and maximum values defined in these options.

## Percentage of Workers by Day Type and Work Type

In this section, it is possible to configure the percentage of employees that go to work based on the day of the week. There are four work types: Offices, Commercial, Industry and City Services. The default values were calculated using data from this link: https://www.bls.gov/news.release/flex2.t09.htm

## Performance Impacts
This mods can have a significant impact on the game's performance - specially in big cities. If you have issues with performance, I would recommend reducing the lunch break percentage, using "Average Day" setting and disabling the Vacation and Holiday features for work and school. The lunch break feature has a significant impact on performance during the middle of the day and it is recommended to keep that percentage with a lower value.

This mod is compatible with the Traffic Simulation Adjuster mod. However, both of them together will have performance impacts and you could adjust that mod's settings to try to improve performance as well.

## Mod Effects
You should expect to see less trips at night and a significant increase in rush hour traffic.

If you enable this mod in an existing city it will take a day or two for you to notice a change in the time of day activity.

The External Trips feature will not worked correctly if used with the Demand Master Pro mod.

If that feature is not used, there should be no conflict. The compatability issues will be greater in an existing city, a new city with these mods will probably function correctly, but I have not tested it.s

## Explaining the Plots

In one of the screenshots above there are four plots comparing the mod in its default settings with the vanilla game in a test city with a population of 20,000. In those plots, trips are classified based on their origin and destination and below is a brief explanation of what each one of them mean. The plots were done using data from the TripsData mod.

* **Home Based Work:** This include trips from Home to Work and from Work to Home.
* **Home Based School:** This include trips from Home to School and School to Home.
* **Home Based Other:** This consists of trips that start or end at home and go to or are from anyplace that is **not** work or school. This will include trips from home to shopping or leisure, for example. This plot shows the significant reduction of shopping and leisure trips from midnight to 6 AM with the "Disable Early Shopping/Leisure" feature.
* **Non Home Based:** All trips that don't have home as the origin or destination. In this plot you will notice a peak between noon and 2 PM, which consists of the lunch break - which are trips from work to shopping or leisure and back to work.

There are also other four plots comparing the three day types: Weekday, Average Day and Weekend.
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail2.jpg" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/specialevents.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_hbw.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_hbs.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_hbo.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_nhb.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_hbw_dt.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_hbs_dt.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_hbo_dt.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_nhb_dt.png" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/time2work-mod.1655887/" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="1.8" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.2.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="75426" />
	<ChangeLog>
* Fixed infinite shopping time bug
* Added shopping time for cims that go shopping for leisure
* Fixed bug with higher weights when special events are happening
* Added shopping for leisure type variation by time of day
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/ruzbeh0/Time2Work" />
	<ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.com/channels/1024242828114673724/1224077120641302558" />
	<ExternalLink Type="paypal" Url="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/ruzbeh0" />	
	<ExternalLink Type="kofi" Url="https://ko-fi.com/ruzbeh0" />
</Publish>
