<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="77171" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Time2Work" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="This mod allows you to configure the time that cims go to work." />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
This mod has several options to configure cims' work and school schedule and also some options to adjust their behaviour for shopping and leisure. Another feature is the ability to change the simulation to function either as an Average Day, a Weekday, a Weekend or follow a Weekly pattern.

## Work

* **Work Shifts:** Cims go to work based on three shifts: Day, Evening and Night. This mod allows you to configure the percentage of each of those work shifts, the base game has around 20-25% of work trips being at either the Evening or at Night. The mod options menu will allow you to set the percentage for Evening and Night shifts. Day shift percentage will correspond to the remaining percentage points. The default values of the mod are set for 6% for Evening shifts and 4% for Night shifts. These values come from a US Survey which can be found in this link: https://redline.digital/shift-work-statistics/
* **Work Arrival / Departure:** The "Delay/Early factor" adds greater variation to cims work arrival and departure times. The arrival/departure times are implemented using a normal distribution and it works differently in the morning and evening commutes to reflect the real world. In real cities, the evening commute tends to be more spread out than the morning commute, this happens because although most workers have a set time to arrive at work, when it is time to leave work the departure time is not as strict, with a few workers working a few extra minutes or hours. This feature is also implemented differently for each shift. The Evening and Night shifts have even greater variation, spreading out the start and end work times for the cims that work during those shifts.
* **Lunch Break:** The lunch break option will add the possibility of some cims to leave work around noon for either Leisure or Shopping. The break lasts around an hour, after that, they will return to work. The lunch break can be configured by setting the lunch break probability in the mod's menu. Also, cims that take a lunch break, might leave work a little later (to compensate for the time that they weren't working).
* **Work Start/End Time Settings:** This option allows the user to change work start and end times for the day shift.

## Shopping and Leisure

* **Disable Early Shopping or Leisure:** This option will significantly reduce shopping and leisure trips happening between Midnight and 6 AM. With this option, those trips will mostly start between 8 to 10 AM.
* **Vacation and Holiday System:** The vanilla game simulation works as a combination of a Weekday and a Weekend, with work and schools trips having a certain probability of not happening assuming that that cim is taking a day off. The vanilla probability is around 60% of not going to work or school. With vacation and holidays default settings, that probability will be around 30% for work trips.

## School
* **School Vacation System** This feature works similar to the vacation and holiday system for work, with the difference that on Weekends schools are assumed to be closed.
* **School Start/End Time Settings:** This option allows the user to change school start and end times.

## Day Type Simulation

The options in this tab will allow you to change the simulation from an Average Day, a Weekday or a Weekend. And even allow you to simulate a week rotating from Weekdays (Monday to Friday) and Weekends (Saturday and Sunday).

An Average Day, is similar to the vanilla default setting. It consists of a combination of Weekday and Weekends behavior, with around 30% of cims behaving as on a weekend and the rest as on a weekday.

On a Weekday, most of the trips will be work or school related. On a Weekend, there will be more Leisure and Shopping trips. Schools are closed on Weekends.

Note that if the 7 Day Week option is selected, currently, there is no place in the UI that will indicate if the current day is a weekday or a weekend. However, that will be indicated in the Mod's log.

## Mod Effects

This mods can have a significant impact on the game's performance. You should expect to see less trips at night and a significant increase in rush hour traffic.

If you enable this mod in an existing city it will take a day or two for you to notice a change in the time of day activity.

## Explaining the Plots

In one of the screenshots above there are four plots comparing the mod in its default settings with the vanilla game in a test city with a population of 20,000. In those plots, trips are classified based on their origin and destination and below is a brief explanation of what each one of them mean:

* **Home Based Work:** This include trips from Home to Work and from Work to Home.
* **Home Based School:** This include trips from Home to School and School to Home.
* **Home Based Other:** This consists of trips that start or end at home and go to or are from anyplace that is **not** work or school. This will include trips from home to shopping or leisure, for example. This plot shows the significant reduction of shopping and leisure trips from midnight to 6 AM with the "Disable Early Shopping/Leisure" feature.
* **Non Home Based:** All trips that don't have home as the origin or destination. In this plot you will notice a peak between noon and 2 PM, which consists of the lunch break - which are trips from work to shopping or leisure and back to work.
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot_options.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot1.png" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/time2work-mod.1655887/" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="0.4" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.1.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="77209" />
	<ChangeLog>
* Reduced trips being generated at midnight.
* Added option to limit shopping and leisure trips in the early morning.
* Added options to choose start and end hours for work and school.
* Added Day Type Simulation (Average Day, Weekday, Weekend, Week)
* Added vacation and holiday system for work and school.
* Optimized work arrival and departure times.
* Added Portuguese Localization.
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/ruzbeh0/Time2Work" />
</Publish>
